{"posts":[{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"c programming questions","salience":0.5271773338317871,"theta":1},{"name":"helper functions","salience":0.15058255195617676,"theta":1},{"name":"answers","salience":0.1402682065963745,"theta":1},{"name":"libraries","salience":0.10667629539966583,"theta":1},{"name":"reason","salience":0.07529562711715698,"theta":1}],"question":"for the c programming questions can we implement our own helper functions and then call them in our answers can we also include any extra libraries if for whatever reason we decide to","answers":["yes and yes"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"answer","salience":0.13230571150779724,"theta":1},{"name":"page","salience":0.08173488080501556,"theta":1},{"name":"question","salience":0.060619715601205826,"theta":1},{"name":"part","salience":0.05350910499691963,"theta":1},{"name":"im","salience":0.05350910499691963,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.05028210207819939,"theta":1},{"name":"process","salience":0.04391486197710037,"theta":1},{"name":"pages","salience":0.032006800174713135,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.03069513663649559,"theta":1},{"name":"set","salience":0.025747714564204216,"theta":1},{"name":"process","salience":0.025747714564204216,"theta":1},{"name":"variables","salience":0.023648951202630997,"theta":1},{"name":"array","salience":0.023518085479736328,"theta":1},{"name":"pages","salience":0.022001247853040695,"theta":1},{"name":"pages","salience":0.02173592336475849,"theta":1},{"name":"pages","salience":0.02173592336475849,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.021093538030982018,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.021093538030982018,"theta":1},{"name":"data","salience":0.019954310730099678,"theta":1},{"name":"sum","salience":0.017890844494104385,"theta":1},{"name":"process","salience":0.017460696399211884,"theta":1},{"name":"set","salience":0.017460696399211884,"theta":1},{"name":"sum","salience":0.016230622306466103,"theta":1},{"name":"int","salience":0.016230622306466103,"theta":1},{"name":"page","salience":0.0152753796428442,"theta":1},{"name":"array","salience":0.014816578477621078,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.0146423215046525,"theta":1},{"name":"window","salience":0.01401812955737114,"theta":1},{"name":"values","salience":0.013028379529714584,"theta":1},{"name":"sum","salience":0.012259995564818382,"theta":1},{"name":"all","salience":0.011189187876880169,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.01027507521212101,"theta":1},{"name":"registers","salience":0.009835783392190933,"theta":1},{"name":"system","salience":0.006895275786519051,"theta":1},{"name":"piece","salience":0.006895275786519051,"theta":1},{"name":"pages","salience":0.006568775977939367,"theta":1},{"name":"bigarray","salience":0.004923252388834953,"theta":1},{"name":"questions","salience":0.004923252388834953,"theta":1},{"name":"assumptions","salience":0.004325481131672859,"theta":1}],"question":"i m confused abut the part a of this tutorial question why the answer is 2 instead of 99 1 page for the code and 98 pages for the big array the working set of a process could be defined as the set of pages being referenced by the process over a small window of time this would naturally include the pages containing the code being executed and the pages holding the data being accessed by this code consider the following code which computes the sum of all values in a very large array int bigarray 100000 int sum 0 for int i 0 i lt 100000 i sum bigarray i answer the questions below under the assumptions that pages are 4kb all of the above code fits in a single page the sum and i variables are implemented in registers there is just one process running in the system how large is the working set of this piece of code","answers":["from my understanding you just need 2 because when the os is managing each process you only ever need to see the code you re looking at 1 page and then 1 other page for the array part you re looking at the whole thing with the working set model is that you don t or should not load all pages up because that is unnecessary since you only will look at each page in terms of the array section maybe once and if they are needed to be looked at again then they will be loaded up again otherwise the remaining total pages in the whole system could would be allocated to other segments for other processes",["correct the two pages are the page containing the code for the for loop plus the page containing the section of the array that you re currently looking at",["when talking about the valgrind memory leak is that detected from the physical memory or the virtual memory",["process memory"]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"check q1","salience":0.3208720088005066,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.14670436084270477,"theta":1},{"name":"exam","salience":0.10045848786830902,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.09862823784351349,"theta":1},{"name":"output","salience":0.07097171992063522,"theta":1},{"name":"input","salience":0.0625026598572731,"theta":1},{"name":"trick","salience":0.05606209859251976,"theta":1},{"name":"running check","salience":0.049996014684438705,"theta":1},{"name":"tests","salience":0.04731699079275131,"theta":1},{"name":"output","salience":0.04648743197321892,"theta":1}],"question":"when i use check q1 on the sample exams 5 released for the prac exam they are all showing failed tests although i am sure the code is correct as they produce correct output if i manually insert input and crosscheck with output is there a trick to running check","answers":["are you sure it s not just the loading message at the start of the output alternatively trailing spaces or non printing characters are you cross checking using your eyes easily deceived or using diff"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"way","salience":0.5820137858390808,"theta":1},{"name":"mips","salience":0.25505372881889343,"theta":1},{"name":"asciiz array","salience":0.16293247044086456,"theta":1}],"question":"what is the proper way to access asciiz array in mips","answers":["it s just an array of bytes terminated by a 0 byte if you want one of the bytes try lb"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"program","salience":0.5977569222450256,"theta":1},{"name":"code fragment","salience":0.06143151596188545,"theta":1},{"name":"questions","salience":0.04554188251495361,"theta":1},{"name":"aim","salience":0.04010875150561333,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.03772742301225662,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.025652308017015457,"theta":1},{"name":"question","salience":0.01952020451426506,"theta":1},{"name":"t","salience":0.018200870603322983,"theta":1},{"name":"code fragment","salience":0.017093226313591003,"theta":1},{"name":"program","salience":0.01648436114192009,"theta":1},{"name":"order","salience":0.014635914005339146,"theta":1},{"name":"code fragment","salience":0.014604650437831879,"theta":1},{"name":"question","salience":0.01232267264276743,"theta":1},{"name":"t","salience":0.011910137720406055,"theta":1},{"name":"programming logic","salience":0.010484430007636547,"theta":1},{"name":"case","salience":0.010041767731308937,"theta":1},{"name":"executable","salience":0.009800040163099766,"theta":1},{"name":"syntax errors","salience":0.008569914847612381,"theta":1},{"name":"semi colon","salience":0.006963186431676149,"theta":1},{"name":"bracket","salience":0.006963186431676149,"theta":1},{"name":"programming logic","salience":0.005555751733481884,"theta":1},{"name":"code fragment","salience":0.004526885692030191,"theta":1},{"name":"question","salience":0.004103983286768198,"theta":1}],"question":"looking through the sample exams there are a few questions that ask us to write a code fragment the question doesn t say write a full program which would involve writing all required code in order to have a working executable this implies to me we don t have to compile the code fragment we submit as it won t be a complete program that being the case is the code fragment expected to be syntactically perfect or is the aim of the question to demonstrate the programming logic required to achieve what the question asks without compiling the code fragment there is a high likelihood there will be atleast one or two small syntax errors i e missing bracket or semi colon so i would like to understand is this particularly important or should we just be focusing on the programming logic in what we submit","answers":["if it s not a prac question then i won t be expecting syntactic perfection"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"terminator","salience":0.31477391719818115,"theta":1},{"name":"data section","salience":0.11448301374912262,"theta":1},{"name":"advice","salience":0.09042485058307648,"theta":1},{"name":"above","salience":0.08623335510492325,"theta":1},{"name":"error","salience":0.07934445887804031,"theta":1},{"name":"mips code data nterm byte","salience":0.07840476930141449,"theta":1},{"name":"syntax","salience":0.07298856228590012,"theta":1},{"name":"number","salience":0.0553959496319294,"theta":1},{"name":"terminator","salience":0.04433782771229744,"theta":1},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.03902602195739746,"theta":1},{"name":"char","salience":0.024587266147136688,"theta":1}],"question":"how can we define the null terminator in the data section of our mips code data nterm byte 0 the above throws an error invalid syntax please advice are we explicitly supposed to check against char 0 or the number 0 when looking for the null terminator thanks","answers":["just use the number 0 i e nterm byte 0",["thanks jas"]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"answer","salience":0.29430055618286133,"theta":1},{"name":"size","salience":0.1515812873840332,"theta":1},{"name":"q3 ci","salience":0.05930553749203682,"theta":1},{"name":"2017s2 practice exam","salience":0.05930553749203682,"theta":1},{"name":"component","salience":0.05442701280117035,"theta":1},{"name":"components","salience":0.05442701280117035,"theta":1},{"name":"size","salience":0.05077009275555611,"theta":1},{"name":"piece","salience":0.04341224953532219,"theta":1},{"name":"components","salience":0.03793659061193466,"theta":1},{"name":"memory","salience":0.03756100311875343,"theta":1},{"name":"all","salience":0.032305359840393066,"theta":1},{"name":"padding","salience":0.028428146615624428,"theta":1},{"name":"compiler","salience":0.028367318212985992,"theta":1},{"name":"fields","salience":0.01997561752796173,"theta":1},{"name":"size","salience":0.01879885420203209,"theta":1},{"name":"answers","salience":0.016541384160518646,"theta":1},{"name":"struct","salience":0.012556442990899086,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i m not too sure why the answer to q3 c i on the 2017s2 practice exam is 8bytes your answers say it s the size of the largest component all components share the same piece of memory i thought the size of a struct is the size of all of its components added together padding if the compiler doesnt re arrange the fields","answers":["it s not a struct it s a union big difference",[""]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"memory","salience":0.2698907256126404,"theta":1},{"name":"memory","salience":0.25226688385009766,"theta":1},{"name":"middle","salience":0.22259795665740967,"theta":1},{"name":"memory","salience":0.1433713585138321,"theta":1},{"name":"another","salience":0.1118730828166008,"theta":1}],"question":"curious about 17s2 q7 why there is a empty memory in the middle of the physical memory isn t physical memory filled up one after another","answers":["the contents of physical memory evolves as processes come and go process pages are allocated to whatever frames happen to be free at the time they re needed so they won t necessarily be allocated to consecutive frames in memory this physical memory might have an empty frame because some process just finished and released it",["i see thanks a lot"]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"something","salience":0.36035338044166565,"theta":1},{"name":"sample","salience":0.17144928872585297,"theta":1},{"name":"c","salience":0.06863506138324738,"theta":1},{"name":"lectures","salience":0.06816855818033218,"theta":1},{"name":"decimal","salience":0.06816855818033218,"theta":1},{"name":"memory","salience":0.04700371250510216,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.04644068330526352,"theta":1},{"name":"scanf","salience":0.04319849982857704,"theta":1},{"name":"testing c isn t","salience":0.03782057762145996,"theta":1},{"name":"void","salience":0.032702572643756866,"theta":1},{"name":"amp b amp c printf","salience":0.02298412285745144,"theta":1},{"name":"nabcc 0 n scanf ddd","salience":0.01943851262331009,"theta":1},{"name":"nc dnnabc","salience":0.013636475428938866,"theta":1}],"question":"why in qn4b of the sample is c set to 0 i recall in the lectures something about it stopping once it sees the decimal and when i compiled and ran some code to test c was set to 1 i presume what was held in the memory beforehand after some further testing c isn t being changed by the scanf at all so only when i initialise c to 0 as below it still spits out c 0 include lt stdio h gt int main void int n a b c c 0 n scanf d d d amp a amp b amp c printf n d na d nb d nc d n n a b c return 0","answers":["it read 42 and assigns that to a it reads 64 and assigns that to b it stops at the because that character is not a valid char to find in a decimal integer when it tries to find a value for c it looks at the and says hmmm not an integer and gives up without changing c",["thanks so to confirm the solutions where it says 0 for should be a instead since c is uninitialised https cgi cse unsw edu au cs1521 18s2 exams sample soln q4 soln txt",["in the code you posted c is initialised to 0",["but not in the actual question s code sorry upon rereading i realised my question wasn t particularly clear https cgi cse unsw edu au cs1521 18s2 exams sample q04 html",["in that case or undefined or garbage would be acceptable"]]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"mistake","salience":0.3776853680610657,"theta":1},{"name":"technicality","salience":0.13907812535762787,"theta":1},{"name":"practice paper","salience":0.1233995258808136,"theta":1},{"name":"binary","salience":0.08543767780065536,"theta":1},{"name":"octal","salience":0.08543767780065536,"theta":1},{"name":"wolframalpha","salience":0.07857929915189743,"theta":1},{"name":"question","salience":0.041974280029535294,"theta":1},{"name":"im","salience":0.041974280029535294,"theta":1},{"name":"answers","salience":0.026433758437633514,"theta":1}],"question":"is there a mistake in q6e from the practice paper when i convert the 2 s complement binary straight into octal i get 177634 confirmed with wolframalpha vs the 177632 which the answers suggest or is there some technicality in this question which i m overlooking","answers":["no it was wrong and i ve fixed it"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"questions","salience":0.2512265741825104,"theta":1},{"name":"answer","salience":0.15900567173957825,"theta":1},{"name":"process","salience":0.07183850556612015,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exam e sigtstp user types","salience":0.06338124722242355,"theta":1},{"name":"z","salience":0.06338124722242355,"theta":1},{"name":"terminal","salience":0.06338124722242355,"theta":1},{"name":"action","salience":0.05938870832324028,"theta":1},{"name":"man page","salience":0.049630697816610336,"theta":1},{"name":"process","salience":0.04903874173760414,"theta":1},{"name":"action","salience":0.047875385731458664,"theta":1},{"name":"man page","salience":0.03457578644156456,"theta":1},{"name":"theorem questions","salience":0.03063306026160717,"theta":1},{"name":"program","salience":0.026629991829395294,"theta":1},{"name":"octal","salience":0.01655988022685051,"theta":1},{"name":"way","salience":0.013453242368996143,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i have 2 questions about the answer of sample exam e sigtstp user types control z in controlling terminal suspend process for this one why the action is not stop the process i think in the man page the default action is stop e 100 16 0xff9c 100 8 0177632 100 2 1111 1111 1001 1100 and for this one i think the octal should be 0177634 by the way just to make sure we are allowed to use man page and writing a program to do the theorem questions right thank you","answers":["depends what you mean by stop in this context stop ping a process means halting execution but leaving the process active the process can be restarted from the point it was stopped i d call this suspended the man page calls it stopped yes 0177632 is a typo i ve changed it 0177634 and yes as i ve said quite a few times you have access to the unix man pages during the exam",["okay thank you"]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"exam im","salience":0.1389179825782776,"theta":1},{"name":"type argument","salience":0.13368046283721924,"theta":1},{"name":"question","salience":0.12163767218589783,"theta":1},{"name":"point structure","salience":0.08522237092256546,"theta":1},{"name":"temptl gt coord gt","salience":0.055091917514801025,"theta":1},{"name":"issues","salience":0.04837065190076828,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.04837065190076828,"theta":1},{"name":"point temptl","salience":0.04812239110469818,"theta":1},{"name":"coord","salience":0.046974629163742065,"theta":1},{"name":"ddn","salience":0.03780140355229378,"theta":1},{"name":"error","salience":0.034733258187770844,"theta":1},{"name":"error messages","salience":0.030568718910217285,"theta":1},{"name":"data structure","salience":0.02627762407064438,"theta":1},{"name":"understanding","salience":0.023114876821637154,"theta":1},{"name":"gt coord gt y","salience":0.022835154086351395,"theta":1},{"name":"im","salience":0.018457792699337006,"theta":1},{"name":"something","salience":0.018457792699337006,"theta":1},{"name":"gt","salience":0.017008857801556587,"theta":1},{"name":"ddn temptl gt coord gt","salience":0.017008857801556587,"theta":1},{"name":"someone","salience":0.0157482847571373,"theta":1},{"name":"coord printf","salience":0.011598654091358185,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i have a question about q2 of the 17s2 exam i m confused as to why i m having issues printing the point structure my code reads as follows point temptl while read in temptl sizeof point 0 printf d d n temptl gt coord gt x temptl gt coord gt y my error messages reads q2 c 74 44 error invalid type argument of gt have coord printf d d n temptl gt coord gt x temptl gt coord gt y from my understanding of the data structure this should be fine could someone please tell me if i m missing something","answers":["whilst you ve created temptl as a pointer temptl coord is not a pointer so using gt notation isn t valid to access the x and y values so instead of temptl gt coord gt x try temptl gt coord x and same for the y",["ahhh thank you for that"]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"exe","salience":0.5061643123626709,"theta":1},{"name":"advice","salience":0.3273385167121887,"theta":1},{"name":"scripts","salience":0.16649717092514038,"theta":1}],"question":"how are we meant to install the exe and check scripts please advice thanks","answers":["you don t need to they re in cs1521 bin fix your path"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"mergesort","salience":0.2665513753890991,"theta":1},{"name":"function mergesort","salience":0.151363343000412,"theta":1},{"name":"exam","salience":0.12947843968868256,"theta":1},{"name":"answer","salience":0.07800295203924179,"theta":1},{"name":"cse machine","salience":0.07257651537656784,"theta":1},{"name":"make","salience":0.062053319066762924,"theta":1},{"name":"sorting function","salience":0.054989781230688095,"theta":1},{"name":"mergesort","salience":0.051649753004312515,"theta":1},{"name":"exam","salience":0.043965861201286316,"theta":1},{"name":"advance","salience":0.03867882862687111,"theta":1},{"name":"mergesort","salience":0.03254673257470131,"theta":1},{"name":"declaration","salience":0.018143102526664734,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i would like to ask if the built in function mergesort can be used in exam i found in the answer there is qsort i used mergesort on 17s2 q3 however it doesn t compile on cse machine with make telling implicit declaration of mergesort so is it ok to use built in sorting function such as mergesort in exam thanks in advance","answers":["it s fine to use ant sorting function from the library but as i said elsewhere i d be disappointed if you couldn t produce a bubble sort yourself"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"program","salience":0.5286484956741333,"theta":1},{"name":"practice prac exams","salience":0.1087164506316185,"theta":1},{"name":"q1","salience":0.10745230317115784,"theta":1},{"name":"test","salience":0.10745230317115784,"theta":1},{"name":"output","salience":0.08648256957530975,"theta":1},{"name":"output","salience":0.06124788522720337,"theta":1}],"question":"hello i can t figure out why my program for q1 in practice prac exams can t pass the test even it has the same output with the expected output gt lt","answers":["as jas has stated the expected output contains a line the loaded one which is filtered out of your output by check feel free to change the expected output files and remove the loaded lines if you want the satisfaction of seeing test x passed so in the expected file there is the line loaded home class lib exceptions so neglecting that it looks like you have the correct output could also delete that line from the expected files",["thx mate"]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"answers","salience":1,"theta":1}],"question":"hello i was wondering where the 8 came from in the answers for q4bi 17s2 i 68 4 20 20 1 3 4 1 3 4 8 thanks liz","answers":["the major field was 6 bytes need to round up to a multiple of 4",["i am still a little confused about this i know from the lectures that character pointers can be any number so is this a principle of arrays structs or something else i e do we want the 68 to be a multiple of 4 or the 8 to be a multiple of 4 if for example the array was of size 2 characters would it be rounded up to 4 also is there a name for this principle so i can do some further reading thanks",["it s because we want the total size of the struct to be a multiple of 4 so that we can put structs one after another in memory without needing padding between them character arrays can be any length you want whether padding is needed after them depends on what kind of value is following or on whether it s the last field in the struct",["thanks"]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"questions","salience":0.3973293900489807,"theta":1},{"name":"exam","salience":0.16811856627464294,"theta":1},{"name":"files","salience":0.11610055714845657,"theta":1},{"name":"directories","salience":0.11413613706827164,"theta":1},{"name":"q1 q2 etc","salience":0.10821619629859924,"theta":1},{"name":"directories","salience":0.06461194902658463,"theta":1},{"name":"someone","salience":0.03148721531033516,"theta":1}],"question":"the questions in sample final exam refer to files is directories called q1 q2 etc can someone tell me where these directories are","answers":["they don t exist however i think at least one of the questions was like one of the practice prac exam questions so you can use the files for them you could always take the solution files remove the appropriate function then try to recreate what it did"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"something","salience":0.18291199207305908,"theta":1},{"name":"operations","salience":0.18291199207305908,"theta":1},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.08284919708967209,"theta":1},{"name":"i","salience":0.07311371713876724,"theta":1},{"name":"o wronly o creat","salience":0.07056928426027298,"theta":1},{"name":"exam","salience":0.056592509150505066,"theta":1},{"name":"example","salience":0.056592509150505066,"theta":1},{"name":"ii","salience":0.049865540117025375,"theta":1},{"name":"c","salience":0.04639202356338501,"theta":1},{"name":"solution","salience":0.044498756527900696,"theta":1},{"name":"o wronly o creat","salience":0.04369049891829491,"theta":1},{"name":"o creat","salience":0.03513922169804573,"theta":1},{"name":"solution","salience":0.028089230880141258,"theta":1},{"name":"numbers","salience":0.02741466462612152,"theta":1},{"name":"printf o wronly o creat","salience":0.019368864595890045,"theta":1}],"question":"i m not getting something about the bitwise operations on the i assume octal numbers here in q5 comp1521 17s2 final exam for example the solution for ii is given as o wronly o creat or 00000101 but when i try to replicate that in c with printf o wronly o creat is o n o wronly o creat i get o wronly o creat is 1001 how are the numbers in the solution generated","answers":["how are the numbers in the solution generated i got them off a man page if i remember correctly maybe some unix system defines the symbolic names differently or maybe i copied them wrong either way you should work with whatever values are given and answer relative to those i was actually expecting symbolic answers rather than numeric if you simply wrote 00001001 as your answer i would assume that you d messed up the bitwise or and mark it wrong if you want to write a program that gives you a different result say how you generated this result e g give your one liner and if it s valid then i d mark it as correct note if i run your program on williams cse unsw edu au it gives 00000101",["what do you know the results on different systems must be different ok that clears it up a bit i guess i ll stick to symbolic answers if it comes up thanks",["though the answer given for i looks wrong no matter what o rdwr o append or 00000102 looking at the given defines and also the output on weill is should definitely be 00002002",["fixed thanks"]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"page table entries","salience":0.26329857110977173,"theta":1},{"name":"pages","salience":0.22949334979057312,"theta":1},{"name":"page table entries","salience":0.18618018925189972,"theta":1},{"name":"space","salience":0.115348219871521,"theta":1},{"name":"page table entires","salience":0.08148753643035889,"theta":1},{"name":"page","salience":0.07272715121507645,"theta":1},{"name":"process","salience":0.0514649897813797,"theta":1}],"question":"hi for 2017 q7b why is there 8 page table entries and 5 page table entries contain loaded pages i noticed that there is an empty page in process address space why not 7 page table entires thanks","answers":["there are 8 page table entries for the process address space and there are 5 memory frames in the physical memory only 7 of the pages in the process address space are currently in use the other page might eventually have stuff put into it if e g enough objects are created with malloc",["but why not 6 memory frames in the physical memory including the empty one",["the number of memory frames is determined by the size of physical memory it has no correlation with the size of any process address space"]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"tar","salience":0.4861890375614166,"theta":1},{"name":"vlab","salience":0.10779030621051788,"theta":1},{"name":"questions","salience":0.09418504685163498,"theta":1},{"name":"home","salience":0.09418504685163498,"theta":1},{"name":"exam files","salience":0.07264857739210129,"theta":1},{"name":"vlab","salience":0.06808754801750183,"theta":1},{"name":"lot","salience":0.032106664031744,"theta":1},{"name":"error","salience":0.02457985281944275,"theta":1},{"name":"download page","salience":0.020227914676070213,"theta":1}],"question":"dr shepherd i am working on these questions at home using vlab how am i able to install the exam files files tar into vlab if i try to access the download page in vlab it will just give me error thanks a lot","answers":["i don t know why you all seem to think there s something magical about the vlab environment it just gives you a virtual screen which is equivalent to sitting on a cse workstation and doing things what kind of error does the download page give and how are you trying to access it",["i do not know what is happening here i just clicked on the files tar icon on the cs1521 page",["this is a browser problem rather than a vlab problem an easy way to get the exam tar file would be to run the command cp cs1521 web 18s2 exams 17s2final files exam tar or even better make a directory where you want to work on the exam change into that directory and then run the command tar xf cs1521 web 18s2 exams 17s2final files exam tar and it will put all of the relevant files in your directory",["thank you so much dr shepherd"]]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"q4 ai","salience":0.3392890393733978,"theta":1},{"name":"number","salience":0.2579383850097656,"theta":1},{"name":"flip digits","salience":0.1421232968568802,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exam","salience":0.1421232968568802,"theta":1},{"name":"solution","salience":0.06945771723985672,"theta":1},{"name":"calculation","salience":0.04906827211380005,"theta":1}],"question":"for q4 a i in 2017 sample exam 00000000000000000000000000101010 flip digits gt 11111111 11111111 11111111 11010101 add 1 gt 11111111 11111111 11111111 11010110 which is a huge number instead of 42 in the solution what is wrong with my calculation thank you","answers":["you misread the question what i wanted was for you interpret the bit string as a number x in twos complement format what you ve done is negate the number and given x i was asking you tell me what x was",["hi in the 2017 sample exam q6d write a recursive function to free the memory associated with a list i e free all of the node s use the following function header void freenodes node l the solution is void freenodes node l if l null freenodes l gt next free l i don t quite understand how it is recursive isn t it just freeing l and l gt next what if there exists l gt next gt next thanks",["it s recursive because it calls itself as long as the list isn t empty which happens when the recursion winds its way to the end of the list comp1521 doesn t cover recursion much or linked lists but comp1511 does afaik"]]]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"decimal","salience":0.2490762174129486,"theta":1},{"name":"answer","salience":0.15008579194545746,"theta":1},{"name":"answer","salience":0.09920241683721542,"theta":1},{"name":"answers","salience":0.08722253888845444,"theta":1},{"name":"bits","salience":0.08274871110916138,"theta":1},{"name":"digit","salience":0.07135872542858124,"theta":1},{"name":"question","salience":0.07051832228899002,"theta":1},{"name":"b","salience":0.06567221134901047,"theta":1},{"name":"thanks","salience":0.05173188075423241,"theta":1},{"name":"bits","salience":0.03718404844403267,"theta":1},{"name":"advance","salience":0.035199124366045,"theta":1}],"question":"for 2017 sample q6 converting 100 in decimal to octal why answer is 0144 rather than 144 also for all other answers in this question there are all one 0 in the left most digit and for question7 b why the answer could be 0 isn t like lb loads bits from lower to higher up to 8 bits so that 1001 1010 can only be loaded thanks in advance","answers":["0144 is to make the point that it s octal since a leading 0 is how you indicate octal in c on some architectures it could be zero of course we re dealing with mips and so it can t i assume that you wrote a small mips program to check","got the idea of 0 for signed octal"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"solutions","salience":1,"theta":1}],"question":"are solutions for this going to be released","answers":["they re now there follow the solutions link","only after you ve attempted the questions"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"answer","salience":0.3047831058502197,"theta":1},{"name":"rmm0d function","salience":0.15802662074565887,"theta":1},{"name":"output","salience":0.04793749377131462,"theta":1},{"name":"quirk","salience":0.0473504401743412,"theta":1},{"name":"output","salience":0.03254571557044983,"theta":1},{"name":"output","salience":0.03254571557044983,"theta":1},{"name":"im","salience":0.030082151293754578,"theta":1},{"name":"reason","salience":0.026461588218808174,"theta":1},{"name":"cmp","salience":0.026141373440623283,"theta":1},{"name":"cse machines","salience":0.024298977106809616,"theta":1},{"name":"ssh d","salience":0.024298977106809616,"theta":1},{"name":"files","salience":0.024298977106809616,"theta":1},{"name":"exe arrays","salience":0.02204086072742939,"theta":1},{"name":"start","salience":0.020874029025435448,"theta":1},{"name":"bug","salience":0.018701648339629173,"theta":1},{"name":"bin path","salience":0.018352607265114784,"theta":1},{"name":"cs1521","salience":0.018352607265114784,"theta":1},{"name":"default","salience":0.018352607265114784,"theta":1},{"name":"home","salience":0.018352607265114784,"theta":1},{"name":"dr","salience":0.015465382486581802,"theta":1},{"name":"bug","salience":0.014644378796219826,"theta":1},{"name":"anyone","salience":0.01419574674218893,"theta":1},{"name":"code","salience":0.012871128506958485,"theta":1},{"name":"system","salience":0.012871128506958485,"theta":1},{"name":"start q1 command","salience":0.008077062666416168,"theta":1},{"name":"spec","salience":0.008077062666416168,"theta":1}],"question":"hi i ve completed exam1 q1 the rmm0d function is running correctly i think however there seems to be a quirk in the output i get the correct answer however the output differs to the expected output this happens in all cmp does anyone know the reason why this would occur i m running exe arrays s to create the files i m doing this while ssh d into the cse machines i ve tried to use the re start q1 command as suggested in the spec however i don t think re start exists in the default or home cs1521 bin path anymore tl dr is this a bug in my code or a bug in the system","answers":["yes the expected output contains a line the loaded one which is filtered out of your output by check feel free to change the expected output files and remove the loaded lines if you want the satisfaction of seeing test x passed"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"exam spec front sheet","salience":0.3730654716491699,"theta":1},{"name":"calculator apps","salience":0.25617358088493347,"theta":1},{"name":"ones","salience":0.18697039783000946,"theta":1},{"name":"calculator","salience":0.18379054963588715,"theta":1}],"question":"the exam spec front sheet says that calculator apps are available do you know which ones exactly i can use or more specifically will gnome calculator be available","answers":["xcalc and bc"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"script","salience":0.2535417675971985,"theta":1},{"name":"check","salience":0.23084108531475067,"theta":1},{"name":"exe","salience":0.23084108531475067,"theta":1},{"name":"answer","salience":0.21257710456848145,"theta":1},{"name":"17s2 exam","salience":0.07219895720481873,"theta":1}],"question":"i don t understand how could i install the script of check and exe to verify my answer of 17s2 exam should i use chmod 755 or what","answers":["that would certainly help and you could always run them as sh check or sh exe if you copy the scripts into the directory where you re working"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"message","salience":0.20008696615695953,"theta":1},{"name":"tests","salience":0.18669012188911438,"theta":1},{"name":"exp","salience":0.18669012188911438,"theta":1},{"name":"atm","salience":0.1195959523320198,"theta":1},{"name":"function","salience":0.1195959523320198,"theta":1},{"name":"print sth","salience":0.0641988217830658,"theta":1},{"name":"getstudents","salience":0.06342893838882446,"theta":1},{"name":"pointer","salience":0.05971313267946243,"theta":1}],"question":"for practical exam2 q2 the tests 8 exp should it print a message about null empty atm in main function it seems if getstudents return a null pointer it print sth","answers":[]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"files","salience":0.5833078622817993,"theta":1},{"name":"vlab","salience":0.4166921377182007,"theta":1}],"question":"how to install these files into vlab","answers":["which files specifically"]},{"tags":[{"name":"forums","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"sample exams","salience":0.5,"theta":1},{"name":"check","salience":0.6212531328201294,"theta":1},{"name":"program","salience":0.19494661688804626,"theta":1},{"name":"way","salience":0.18380022048950195,"theta":1}],"question":"can t use check is there any other way to check program","answers":["run the tests by hand look at the tests sh files compare your output against the tests exp or whatever they re called files in other words look in the tests directory and work it out from there"]}]}